export const chapter = "Chapter - 16: Air : Composition and Structure  ";
export const noOfActivities = 3;

if (localStorage.getItem("activityNumber") == 1) {
  activityData = {
    activity: "Tick the correct option:",
    questions: [
      {
        question: "What are the three main domains of the Earth?",
        optionA: "Biosphere, Hydrosphere, Atmosphere",
        optionB: "Lithosphere, Hydrosphere, Atmosphere",
        optionC: "Geosphere, Hydrosphere, Thermosphere",
        correctAnswer: "b) Lithosphere, Hydrosphere, Atmosphere",
      },
      {
        question:
          "Which gas constitutes about 78 percent of the Earth's atmosphere?",
        optionA: "Oxygen",
        optionB: "Nitrogen",
        optionC: "Carbon Dioxide",
        correctAnswer: "b) Nitrogen",
      },
      {
        question:
          "What is the importance of the lower layer of the atmosphere?",
        optionA: "Provides sunlight",
        optionB: "Protects from harmful ultraviolet rays",
        optionC: "Generates electricity",
        correctAnswer: "b) Protects from harmful ultraviolet rays",
      },
      {
        question:
          "What is the main process by which plants take in carbon dioxide?",
        optionA: "Respiration",
        optionB: "Photosynthesis",
        optionC: "Combustion",
        correctAnswer: "b) Photosynthesis",
      },
      {
        question: "What is the greenhouse effect?",
        optionA: "Cooling the Earth at night",
        optionB: "Trapping heat in the atmosphere",
        optionC: "Decreasing the Earth's temperature",
        correctAnswer: "b) Trapping heat in the atmosphere",
      },
      {
        question: "What causes global warming?",
        optionA: "Cutting down trees",
        optionB: "Release of carbon dioxide from burning fuels",
        optionC: "Both a and b",
        correctAnswer: "c) Both a and b",
      },
      {
        question:
          "Which layer of the atmosphere contains ozone, protecting us from harmful ultraviolet rays?",
        optionA: "Troposphere",
        optionB: "Stratosphere",
        optionC: "Mesosphere",
        correctAnswer: "b) Stratosphere",
      },
      {
        question: "Where do jet planes usually fly?",
        optionA: "Mesosphere",
        optionB: "Troposphere",
        optionC: "Thermosphere",
        correctAnswer: "b) Troposphere",
      },
      {
        question:
          "In which layer does the temperature decrease with increasing altitude?",
        optionA: "Troposphere",
        optionB: "Stratosphere",
        optionC: "Mesosphere",
        correctAnswer: "a) Troposphere",
      },
      {
        question: "What is the outermost layer of the atmosphere?",
        optionA: "Exosphere",
        optionB: "Thermosphere",
        optionC: "Mesosphere",
        correctAnswer: "a) Exosphere",
      },
    ],
  };
}

if (localStorage.getItem("activityNumber") == 2) {
  activityData = {
    activity: "Fill in the blanks:",
    questions: [
      {
        question:
          "The three domains of the Earth are __________ (land), hydrosphere (water), and atmosphere (air).",
        optionA: "Geosphere",
        optionB: "Lithosphere",
        optionC: "Pedosphere",
        correctAnswer: "Lithosphere",
      },
      {
        question:
          "The atmosphere extends up to a height of __________ km above the surface of the Earth.",
        optionA: "1,000",
        optionB: "1,200",
        optionC: "1,600",
        correctAnswer: "1,600",
      },
      {
        question:
          "The lower layer of the atmosphere contains life-giving __________ which we inhale.",
        optionA: "Carbon Dioxide",
        optionB: "Oxygen",
        optionC: "Nitrogen",
        correctAnswer: "Oxygen",
      },
      {
        question:
          "The atmosphere protects us from harmful __________ rays of the sun.",
        optionA: "Gamma",
        optionB: "Ultraviolet",
        optionC: "Infrared",
        correctAnswer: "Ultraviolet",
      },
      {
        question:
          "The main gases in the air are nitrogen, oxygen, and __________.",
        optionA: "Helium",
        optionB: "Carbon Monoxide",
        optionC: "Carbon Dioxide",
        correctAnswer: "Carbon Dioxide",
      },
      {
        question: "Nitrogen constitutes about __________ percent of the air.",
        optionA: "65%",
        optionB: "78%",
        optionC: "90%",
        correctAnswer: "78%",
      },
      {
        question:
          "All animals and human beings need __________ to breathe and live.",
        optionA: "Nitrogen",
        optionB: "Carbon Dioxide",
        optionC: "Oxygen",
        correctAnswer: "Oxygen",
      },
      {
        question:
          "The interaction between oxygen and carbon dioxide is essential for sustaining __________.",
        optionA: "Water cycle",
        optionB: "Life",
        optionC: "Photosynthesis",
        correctAnswer: "Life",
      },
      {
        question:
          "The greenhouse effect is compared to the warming effect inside a __________.",
        optionA: "Refrigerator",
        optionB: "Oven",
        optionC: "Greenhouse",
        correctAnswer: "Greenhouse",
      },
      {
        question:
          "The outermost layer of the atmosphere, the __________, gradually merges with outer space.",
        optionA: "Troposphere",
        optionB: "Thermosphere",
        optionC: "Exosphere",
        correctAnswer: "Exosphere",
      },
    ],
  };
}

if (localStorage.getItem("activityNumber") == 3) {
  activityData = {
    activity: "Write 'True' for True and 'False' for False statements:",
    questions: [
      {
        question: "The lithosphere is one of the three domains of the Earth.",
        optionA: "True",
        optionB: "False",
        correctAnswer: "True",
      },
      {
        question:
          "The atmosphere extends up to a height of 2,000 km above the Earth's surface.",
        optionA: "True",
        optionB: "False",
        correctAnswer: "False",
      },
      {
        question:
          "Plants release carbon dioxide during the process of photosynthesis.",
        optionA: "True",
        optionB: "False",
        correctAnswer: "False",
      },
      {
        question:
          "The stratosphere is the layer of the atmosphere where jet planes usually fly.",
        optionA: "True",
        optionB: "False",
        correctAnswer: "True",
      },
      {
        question:
          "Mountains, plains, and plateaus are the three main types of landforms on Earth.",
        optionA: "True",
        optionB: "False",
        correctAnswer: "True",
      },
      {
        question:
          "The Ganga-Brahmaputra Plains have been the cradle of great civilizations in history.",
        optionA: "True",
        optionB: "False",
        correctAnswer: "True",
      },
      {
        question:
          "Alluvial soil is rich in iron and suitable for crops like cotton and tobacco.",
        optionA: "True",
        optionB: "False",
        correctAnswer: "False",
      },
      {
        question: "The thermosphere is the coldest layer in the atmosphere.",
        optionA: "True",
        optionB: "False",
        correctAnswer: "False",
      },
      {
        question:
          "Black soil is the most fertile soil in India, suitable for crops like rice, sugarcane, and wheat.",
        optionA: "True",
        optionB: "False",
        correctAnswer: "True",
      },
      {
        question:
          "Soil erosion can be caused by natural factors such as winds and human factors like poor agricultural practices.",
        optionA: "True",
        optionB: "False",
        correctAnswer: "True",
      },
    ],
  };
}

export var activityData;
